# VAMSI KRISHNA TATIKONDA

# SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | TORONTO, ONTARIO

# **Summary**

Highly skilled and forward-thinking Software Developer with 4.5+ years of experience in active development. Has created and delivered solutions to facilitate business growth. Has worked in different industries delivering high-quality software. Excellent at devising clean code in a collaborative environment. Has experience working with multi-cultural and multi-lingual teams.

- Experience in designing, developing API's (RESTful, GraphQL) and building microservices.
- Expertise with integrating different third-party API's.
- Experience with Agile methods, Microservice architecture.
- Positive attitude, responsibility, good decision making, and analytical skills.

# **Employment**

Affinio Inc

Senior Software Developer

Toronto,Ontario,Canada Mar. 2019 to Aug. 2019

 ${\it Scala, Spark, GraphQL/Sangria, Play Framework, Akka Streams, Azure, AWS API's}$ 

- Developed Event-driven microservices and as well as API's (RESTful and GraphQL) primarily using the Scala tech stack.
- Experience with building data pipelines using Spark and Azure and AWS tech stack.
- Building and managing various microservices written in Scala, Java and Spark, Akka Streams
- Responsible for the deployment of the production back-end environment using Azure, DC/OS, Docker.

Software Developer

Toronto,Ontario,Canada Jan. 2018 to Mar. 2019

#### CaseWare International Inc

API/Performance Test Developer

Java, Scala, Gatling, Node. js, Mocha. js

Toronto,Ontario,Canada Jan. 2017 to Jan. 2018

- Developed a microservice using Java, Spring Boot framework to act as a third party API server for Internal use.
- Developed API/Performance tests using Scala, Gatling.
- Developed a command line tool to do Data Integrity Check using Node.js and Mocha.js.

#### Lakehead University

**Programmer Analyst** 

Thunder Bay ,Ontario,Canada Apr. 2016 to Dec. 2016

 ${\tt JavaScript,jQuery,HTML,CSS,UniBasic\ Scripting,Ellucian\ tech\ stack}$ 

- Created and Maintained different ERP components in the University.
- · Wrote custom programs to provide programming solutions for the Various department in the University.
- Tested and Debugged and modified existing web applications.

#### IBM Canada Ltd

Software Developer

Markham,Ontario,Canada May 2014 to Aug. 2015

Java, Eclipse, IBM Rational Application Developer

 Developed new features and fixed defects in performance component within RAD (Eclipse plugin development).

# **Projects**

#### Facebook Messenger Chatbot (Hackathon challenge -Won First Prize)

Node.js| Dialogflow (NLP Framework)

- This project is developed as a part of <u>hackathon challenge</u> to build facebook messenger chatbot using Dialogflow NLP framework and E-commerce store product catalog API(**Shopify API**).
- Facebook Messenger users can chat with the bot to get product information and other information about the store(like hours, contact, shipping, refund etc). watch the demo <a href="https://example.com/here">here</a>.

#### Special Permissions (Lakehead University) ·

HTML |JavaScript | UniData|Scripting

- Developed an end-to-end web application that allows the students to request special permission(s) to enroll in a course when required based on registration rules.
- Created an interface that allows the faculty to review the student's requests based on the approver for the course and student which includes multi-level approval when required and allows faculty to communicate with students using comments and emails.

### **Contact**

■ vamsi1279@gmail.com

**4** 6473231279

in https://ca.linkedin.com/in/vktca

nttps://github.com/vamsikt

# **Education**

Lakehead University
MS Computer Science 2016

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University BS Computer Science 2012

## **Skills**

#### **PROGRAMMING**

Scala •Java •Spark •Play Framework • Akka •SQL
 NoSQL •JavaScript

#### **FAMILIAR**

- •Node •Scripting
- Dialogflow(NLP Framework)

#### **TOOLS**

Testing: •Unit Testing •IBM RQM •Gatling •Mocha js Databases: •SQL Server•Mongo DB

Other: •Git •JIRA •Bitbucket •Jenkins • Eclipse •IBM RAD •IBM RTC

#### CLOUD

Azure • AWS